for us understand that the genealogy the relationships among dinosaurs we use the
لاننا نفهم ان انساب نستخدم العلاقات بين الديناصورات
same techniques and tools
نفس التقنيات والادوات
as other biologists use to understand how different groups of organisms are
باستخدام علماء الاحياء لفهم الاخر كيف مجموعات مختلفة من الكائنات الحية
related
ب
the primary one that we use the technique of cladistic
الاساسية التي نستخدم تقنية cladistic
and park listed is is that we just look at number about repeating the animal
وكله هو اننا ننظر فقط الحيوان في رقم عن المتكرر
and then we try to find the shortest path
ونحن نحاول ان نجد اقصر الطريق
through those attributes when I say shortest path I mean the least
من خلال هذه السمات عندما اقول اعني اقصر المسار الاقل
evolutionary steps
خطوات التطور
I mean for instance if we had you know three animals in
اعني , على سبيل المثال , اذا كان لدينا كما تعلمون الحيوانات في ثلاثة
the room with us now we had say we had a human
الغرفة معنا الان لدينا لدينا الانسان
say we had a a mouse I
كان لدينا فار انا
and say we had with her right well one of the attributes that links the mouse
ولدينا بها احد من الخصائص التي تربط الفار
anti-human together
مضادة للانسان معا
his hair so if you would say that the mouth
شعره اذا كنت اقول ان الفم
in the wizard were most closely related you would have to have to evolutionary
في معظم قرابة كساحر لان التطور
steps the independent or gin up hair
او بخطوات الجن شعر مستقل
but by saying that hair only originate once
ولكن فقط بزمن الشعر مرة
it evidence for a preferential relationship between
هذا الدليل لpreferential العلاقة بين
humans in mouth so that's a very simple example but we do that with hundreds of
البشر في الفم وبسيط جدا المثال ولكننا نفعل ذلك مع مئات
characters in hundreds a battle sometimes
الشخصيات في مئات معركة احيانا
and then we have computer algorithms which actually go through the matrix and
ومن ثم لدينا خوارزميات الكمبيوتر والتي تمر المصفوفة و
find the shortest path through it
نجد اقصر الطريق من خلالها
and results and a family tree up these animals
والنتائج وهذه شجرة العائلة الحيوانات